I'll wipe out all the Fieldsauruses!
我会把菲尔多龙全部歼灭的！
The town has undergone tremendous changes.
这个城镇
I have to deal with the disputes again.
又得去调解纷争了
Yo, Rud.
嗨 路德
That's a troubled face you have there.
你的脸色很不好喔
Bu. Gali.
步、加利
You just became the leader of a clan. This is a bit much on your shoulders, huh?
你才刚成为战团的团长
Maybe you should let someone else handle things?
是不是该交给你以外的人来控管啊？
Yes, about that,
是啊 关于那部分
I have a favor to ask of you.
我有些事想拜托你们
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Oh. Another dispute?
等等 又起纷争了吗？
Yes.
是啊
Well, Fieldsauruses are perfect for making potions and weapons,
毕竟菲尔多龙是个很适合 用来做药水和武器的素材
so it's no surprise everyone's keen to take them down.
难怪大家都抢着要讨伐它
I guess you do need some help
想经营一个战团
to run a clan.
果然必须找人过来帮忙呢
Yes.
对啊
Manicia's handling the day-to-day stuff,
庶务工作目前交给玛妮西娅负责
but we can't let her be too overworked.
但又不能让她太操劳
I asked Lilia, but…
虽然我也问过莉莉亚…
Sorry. My information bank isn't enough to guide you through this.
抱歉
Maybe you should ask the other clans.
不如拜托其他战团帮忙吧
The other clans, huh?
帮忙吗？
Though, the ideal situation would be
不过最理想的状况
to form an alliance with other clans.
还是能结盟之类的
That way, you'll be on equal standing.
这样你们之间就是对等的同盟关系
If you end up under another clan,
如果附属在其他战团底下
it'd defeat the purpose of establishing a new clan.
就会失去在镇上新建一个战团的意义
But if you want allies,
不过想跟其他战团结为同盟
it might be challenging if you don't have something to bring to the table.
如果对方没得到好处 或许很难达成共识
True.
我想也是
Our clan only has Nin, Luna,
毕竟我们战团只有妮恩、露娜
Manicia, and me, after all.
以及玛妮西娅和我而已
If only you had something you could show them right away.
如果你们有可以马上 献给对方的东西就好了
Lily.
-莉莉？
Something we can show the others right now, huh?
我们现在可以马上给对方的东西啊？
Only our combat strength, I think.
也就只有战力了吧
However,
不过因为我们有意包庇玛里乌斯
You have a point.
是啊
we really need someone to guide us on how to manage a clan.
果然还是需要找人 来指导我们怎么经营战团吧
After asking Lilia,
不过听完莉莉亚的建议
I've been putting in the effort.
我也尽自己所能地努力过了
You truly live up to being a clan leader. How dependable.
不愧是战团团长
At this rate,
这样下去
we might just end up becoming a large clan soon.
搞不好意外地 马上就能变成大型战团了
You don't sound too happy about that.
为何用你的语气听起来有点遗憾？
Well, if that happens,
因为那样的话…
we won't get to spend as much time alone together anymore.
可以像这样
Rud.
路德
If you can't find any allies or helpers,
如果你找不到营运的合作伙伴或人手
you can use my identity for publicity.
也可以拿我去宣传喔
I can't do that.
我办不到
You dislike that.
你很讨厌这样吧？
Rud, you really are…
路德 你真的是…
Rud, become the manager of the labyrinth!
路德 来当迷宫管理者吧！
What are you doing?
你们在干吗？
Nothing.
没干吗
Didn't I already refuse?
那件事我不是拒绝过了吗？
I'm quite busy now.
我现在可是很忙的
Then I'll join your clan and help you stop the fights.
那我也加入你的战团
That's not all you do in a clan.
战团又不是只要做那件事就好
By the way, is it okay for the guardian to be wandering around like this?
话说回来 守护者可以这样随意走动吗？
Not a problem at all.
没问题
Then, do you harbor any…
那么你对人类 没有什么怨恨之类的吗？
Are you really asking that?
你真的要问吗？
So, he does.
果然有
Looks like he has a story to tell.
看来之前发生过什么事
Not even the slightest.
-一点怨恨都没有 -搞什么？
So, let me help you.
所以让我帮忙吧
And, in turn, you help me manage the labyrinth.
然后啊 拜托你帮我管理迷宫
Fine.
知道了啦
I'll let you join the clan.
我允许你加入我们
Explain the labyrinth management.
然后再跟我说明一次管理迷宫的事吧
I haven't agreed to become the manager, though.
我还没答应要成为管理者喔
Do you manage the labyrinth from here?
你平时就是在这里管理迷宫吗？
That's right.
没有错
This pond projects the conditions of the labyrinth.
这个池子会倒映出迷宫内部的状况
You adjust the monster configuration and labyrinth structure here.
也可以从这边调整魔物的配置
See the points?
这里不是有点数吗？
You can create or replicate monsters
只要使用点数
just by using points.
就可以制造或复制魔物
Do these points automatically increase?
这点数会自动增加吗？
Points increase over time
随着时间流逝 或是削掉冒险者的护盾
or by depleting an adventurer's shield force.
就能回收点数
I see.
原来如此
So, for example, if you deplete an amount of my shield force,
举例来说 只要你从我身上 削掉大量的护盾
you get an equivalent amount of points?
就能回收同等的点数吗？
Can you demonstrate it to me?
可以实际操作一次给我看吗？
Sure.
好啊
Are you cloning a Goblin?
你要复制哥布林吗？
I'm summoning it into the labyrinth.
是要召唤到迷宫里
-Hey, that will scare off the adventurers. -Ow…
-喂 这样冒险者会跑光的 -好痛
Can you clone other monsters besides Goblins?
哥布林以外的魔物也可以复制吗？
Yes.
可以
The only ones we can currently clone are…
不过现在可以复制的魔物只有…
Goblins, Axe Orcs,
哥布林
Chameleon Kongs,
变色龙金刚
and Fieldsauruses.
菲尔多龙 以上这四种
Only monsters created through Creation can be cloned.
只有那些通过“制造” 获得的自创魔物才可以复制
By the way, if you can establish a trust relationship with monsters,
顺带一提 如果你能跟魔物建立信赖关系
they might help you in dire situations
在紧要关头 对方还会帮助你
and even become quite fond of you.
也有可能变得很亲近你喔
Will monsters really bond with humans?
魔物真的会亲近人类吗？
It costs a million points? It's impossible to create new monsters.
等等 居然要花费一百万点？
That's right.
没错
That's where the grimoire comes in.
此时就要使用这本魔导书
It's an item that can let you randomly create monsters.
这是一个可以随机制造魔物的道具
It's like a lottery.
简单来说就像转蛋
Want to try it?
要试试看吗？
Slime?
史莱姆？
It's a little different from what I said, but it grew attached to you.
虽然跟刚才说的状况有些不同
Does this mean we can create Slimes now?
这样以后就能复制史莱姆了吗？
Correct.
没错
That means
如此一来 只要花一点时间
we may be able to create S-rank monsters.
或许就能制造出S位阶的魔物
Adventurers to Avancia
来阿凡锡亚的冒险者
mostly come for the Fieldsauruses.
多半是为了菲尔多龙而来的
While they're popular now, the flow of people will likely decrease
虽然现在很热闹
once their drop is readily available everywhere.
人流肯定会减少
This way,
如果成为管理者 在迷宫里添加各式各样的魔物
to stabilize the flow of adventurers.
或许能借此稳定冒险者的量
This…
这个应该也能运用在经营战团上
The hit just now recovered 1,000 points.
刚才那一击可以回收一千点
Hey, Rud! I think that little guy's a Rare Slime!
喂 路德 这家伙好像是稀有史莱姆
Creating such a powerful creature. You really struck gold!
制造出这么厉害的家伙 你真是赚到了啊！
Thank you, Slime.
谢谢你 史莱姆
Thanks to you, I've got a great idea.
多亏有你 我想到了一个好主意喔
Marius,
玛里乌斯
I'll manage the labyrinth in your stead.
我就代替你管理迷宫吧
Really?
真的吗？
Not right away. But I'll think about what kind of labyrinth I want to create
虽然不是马上就能帮忙
to attract adventurers.
才能吸引冒险者过来
Can I trouble you to manage it for a while longer?
所以可以麻烦你再管理一段时间吗？
I'll accept that.
好吧 我接受这个条件
What should we do about this little guy?
那这家伙该怎么办才好？
It doesn't like me at all.
毕竟他根本不靠近我
You should take it with you.
不如你就带回家吧
Slime?
史莱姆？
It's okay, Luna.
你别紧张 露娜
Well, um, I ended up with this little thing somehow.
不 那个 这家伙算是我捡到的吧
And Manicia's always wanted a pet…
而且玛妮西娅以前也说过想要养宠物
It looks cuter than the other Slimes out there.
总觉得他好像 比外面的史莱姆来得可爱耶
Aw, so cute.
好可爱喔
Big Brother,
哥哥
if we're keeping it,
如果要把这孩子当宠物养
we should give it a name.
那就必须取个名字吧
You're right.
也是
Master,
主人
you came up with my name almost immediately.
您之前不是很快 就帮我取好名字了吗？
You didn't…
当时该不会…
just pick a name, did you?
是随便取的吧？
No, I didn't!
才不是
I thought it over and came up with a cute name.
我可是经过深思熟虑
I think you said it was because Lunafia petals fell on Miss Luna.
我记得哥哥好像说
That was surprisingly spontaneous of you.
没想到哥哥意外地随便呢
R… Right.
对了 “莱伊姆”这个名字怎么样？
I think it likes it.
看来他似乎很喜欢呢
That's great.
太好了
Nice to meet you, Lime.
请多指教 莱伊姆
I love seeing you flustered.
我最喜欢看哥哥困扰的表情了
Me too.
我也是
Give me a break…
饶了我吧
Avancia's clan leader?
阿凡锡亚的战团团长
An alliance with a clan from such a rural town?
我们为何要跟那种 乡下小镇的战团结盟？
Bu, reject them.
步 去拒绝他
No, wait.
不 等等
This kid seems interesting.
这孩子还挺有趣的嘛
Very well.
好吧
The two major clans will be holding a ball.
过几天有一场两大战团合办的舞会
-Invite them. -Invite them to join us.
-去邀请他过来 -邀他一起来参加吧
Days later,
后来又过了几天
we found ourselves in Keild.
我们来到凯路德镇
This town's bigger than I imagined.
这个城镇比我想象中还大呢
Lilia, Lily,
莉莉亚、莉莉
thank you for coming along.
谢谢你们陪我们来
Don't mention it.
不用客气
We can stop by the guild here too.
反正我们也能顺便 跟这边的公会打个招呼
It's my first time attending a ball.
我还是第一次参加舞会
How exciting, Lilia.
真令人期待呢 姐姐
Rud, what do those flags represent?
路德 那个旗子是什么？
Just like the ones printed here,
就跟这上面印的图案一样
those are the flags of Black Dragon Fang and White Tiger Claw.
那些是象征 黑龙之牙及白虎之爪的旗子
Those flags are everywhere.
两团的旗子都挂得满满的呢
Everyone's here, yes?
所有人都到了吧？
Take a look at these.
你们看这个
They're the invitations to a ball
这是黑龙之牙和白虎之爪
from the two major clans of Keild, Black Dragon Fang and White Tiger Claw.
也就是凯路德的 两大战团寄来的舞会邀请函
Isn't it great, Big Brother?
能收到邀请函 不是很厉害的事吗？哥哥
Though I'm not entirely clear,
虽然不是很清楚
Master is formidable.
但主人果然很强呢
Look.
我说啊
I doubt they're interested in being chummy.
他们肯定不是想一起友好地经营战团
What conditions did they propose?
作为回报 他们提了什么条件？
You're right.
你说得没错
They rejected the alliance proposal.
结盟一事已经被他们拒绝了
They'd consider letting us become their subsidiary.
不过他们说可以考虑
That's not all.
但问题不只如此
In return for their help,
作为帮忙的交换条件
they want Nin.
他们想跟我们索取妮恩
Nin?
索取妮恩？
It's not just the two clans. I've talked to others.
其实不光是两大战团 我也跟其他人提过这件事
But most of them are interested in Nin.
但大部分的人都是冲着妮恩来的
I'm in high demand, after all.
我还真是抢手呢
So, what are you going to do?
所以你打算怎么做？
If you want to go, I won't stop you.
如果你想去的话 我不会挽留你
What if I ask you not to give me up, no matter what?
那如果我拜托你 无论如何都要阻止这种事发生呢？
Then I'll turn them down.
那我当然会阻止
Then reject them.
那就拒绝吧
I don't plan on affiliating myself with any other clan.
我可不打算归属于其他战团喔
I understand.
我知道了
I'll turn them down no matter what.
无论发生什么事 我都会拒绝他们的
But I am prepared to attend the ball,
不过呢
The guests will likely belong
我想舞会的来宾
to either Black Dragon Fang or White Tiger Claw.
应该都是黑龙之牙或白虎之爪的人
I cannot pass up this opportunity
但我不能放过这个
to speak directly to the leaders of the two major clans.
能直接跟两大战团的 代表人对话的机会
You're right.
说得也是
Now is not the time to retreat.
这个时候不该退缩 而是应该主动进攻
Keild…
凯路德
What's wrong?
怎么了吗？
Nothing, just remembered something unimportant.
没什么 只是想起一件不重要的事
with a sentient guardian just like me in that pond.
守护者拥有自我意识的迷宫
And the labyrinth's name is the same as the town called Keild,
而那个迷宫的名字 跟那个叫凯路德的城镇相同
Keild Labyrinth.
叫做凯路德迷宫
That's important information!
这很重要好吗？
Is that so?
很重要吗？
In other words,
也就是说只要攻略凯路德迷宫
and obtain another magic stone,
再拿到一颗魔石的话
perhaps Manicia's illness can be completely cured.
或许就能完全治好玛妮西娅的病了
Keild Labyrinth.
凯路德迷宫
I heard that the two major clans
听说那两大战团
only ever managed to break through to the 50th floor.
似乎也只能突破到第50层
But we've grown a lot during this time.
但是我们这阵子成长了很多
Marius with impeccable firepower,
不仅有火力强到无可挑剔的玛里乌斯
Luna, who practices magic whenever she has free time,
还有只要有空就会练习魔法的露娜
and the excellent healer Nin.
以及优秀的补师 妮恩
We should be able to form a great party.
我们应该可以组成一支很棒的队伍
Raid the labyrinth and find an alliance.
不仅要攻略迷宫 还要找战团结盟
It looks like we're going to have a very interesting trip.
看来这次的旅行会很有趣呢
I'm sure neither will be easy to achieve.
不论是哪一边 肯定都不容易达成
But I must form an alliance with them
但我一定要和他们结盟
and obtain the labyrinth treasure.
还要拿到迷宫秘宝
Sorry to keep you waiting.
让你们久等了
Well? Doesn't it suit me?
怎么样？很适合吧？
It does.
是啊
I did try to get Luna to wear a dress like me.
虽然我是建议过露娜 跟我一起穿礼服啦…
I… I think I look better in this.
我觉得自己比较适合穿这件
You'd look beautiful in a dress, too,
虽然你穿礼服应该也很好看
but the maid outfit suits you.
但女仆装也很适合你喔
Thank… Thank you.…
谢谢您
Lilia, you need to walk with your head held high.
姐姐真是的 走路要抬头挺胸才行
These girly clothes are really not for me.
我不是很喜欢这种女孩子气的衣服
Don't worry, you look adorable.
放心啦 姐姐很可爱喔
Don't keep staring at me.
不要一直看我这边
Lilia is shy.
莉莉亚害羞了
Stop that.
就说了 不要这样啦！
This is a fancy ball.
这个舞会好豪华喔
This all belongs to Black Dragon Fang, after all.
毕竟这些全都是黑龙之牙的东西啊
It really is overwhelming.
真的很惊人呢
I heard White Tiger Claw has similar establishments.
听说白虎之爪也有类似的建筑物喔
Truly the clans that rule above others, huh?
不愧是君临于所有人之上的战团啊
Isn't that Saint Nin?
那不是圣女大人吗？
It is her.
真的耶
Why is she attending our clan's ball?
为什么她会来我们战团的舞会？
Didn't you know?
你不知道吗？
Rumor has it that Saint Nin's clan is becoming a subsidiary of ours.
听说圣女大人的战团 好像要归顺于我们战团喔
Where did that come from?
那是什么谣言？
And they make it sound like Nin's the leader of our clan.
而且说得好像妮恩 才是我们战团的代表人
Leader,
团长 你可不能这样任由他人小看喔
Show them what we're made of.
趁今天让大家对你改观吧
That was the plan.
我也打算妥善处理这个问题
I had prepared myself for this, but it is really uncomfortable here…
虽然早有心理准备
Rud!
话说啊 路德
Can I eat the food over there?
那边的食物可以吃吗？
Yes.
可以
Got it.
这样啊
Marius's really good at easing the tension.
只要有玛里乌斯在 就会变得没那么紧张呢
Yes, we should get some food too.
对啊 我们也去吃点东西吧
Thank you all for attending tonight's ball.
谢谢大家前来参加今天的舞会
I am Cynthia, the subleader of White Tiger Claw.
我是白虎之爪的副团长 辛西娅
We have invited a special guest.
今天我们邀请了特别嘉宾来到现场
Saint Nin,
圣女大人
may we invite you to come on stage?
可以请您上台一下吗？
Rud,
路德
those guys are calling me.
那些家伙好像在叫我上去
But I am Nin from your clan.
但我是你的战团里的妮恩
Yes.
是啊
I'll go and correct them.
我去跟他们抱怨几句
Can you come up with me?
你可以跟我一起上台吗？
Saint Nin,
圣女大人
I didn't expect you to officially become an adventurer.
没想到您居然会正式成为冒险者
It's truly a surprise.
实在让我深感意外
Is that so?
是吗？
I've always wanted to focus on being an adventurer.
我倒是从以前开始 就很想专心当个冒险者了
May I ask who the man next to you is?
那么您身旁的男人是谁？
Who is that guy?
那家伙是谁啊？
He's too close to the saint.
居然跟圣女大人装熟
He is…
-他是… -初次见面
I am Rud, the leader of the clan Nin belongs to.
我是妮恩所属的战团的团长 路德
I remember your class was a tank, right?
我记得你的职业好像是肉盾吧？
The former hero even said you were useless.
前勇者不是说你派不上用场吗？
He consulted me on his party formation issues many times.
当时针对队伍成员的编制问题
So I suggested he just kick out the tank.
所以我就建议他干脆把肉盾开除
What?
-什么？
Raiding labyrinths doesn't require a tank.
因为攻略迷宫不需要肉盾啊
You say it doesn't need a tank?
你说不需要肉盾？
That's right.
是的
The tank is supposed to protect the party from attacks,
因为肉盾表面上 是在守护同伴不受攻击
but in reality, they serve no purpose.
但实际上根本没有在工作
Exactly.
-对啊 能让攻击手顶替肉盾 -要选也会选回避型肉盾
I will cut straight to the point. Saint Nin,
我就单刀直入地说了 妮恩大人
Staying in a no-name clan will only hide your true potential…
待在这种默默无名的战团
to conquer the Keild Labyrinth too.
我们也想要优秀的补师！
Enough.
别说了
I have no intention of handing over Nin.
我并不打算把妮恩交给你们
Mister Rud.
路德先生
Aren't you looking for a clan advisor?
你不是想要一个战团顾问吗？
But you wanted Nin in exchange.
你希望我用妮恩来交换吗？
I'm sorry, but Nin is an important comrade.
很抱歉 但妮恩是我重要的伙伴
I wouldn't trade her for anything.
我不会把她当作交换条件
So, why are you here?
那么你为什么要来这里？
To form an alliance.
我想和你们结盟
An alliance?
结盟？
Is he suggesting an alliance with our clan?
他是想跟我们这个大战团结盟吗？
Isn't he from some weak clan?
他不是乡下的弱小战团吗？
And he's just a tank.
而且还只是个肉盾
This has to be a joke.
他是在开玩笑吧
Just knowing a tank is the clan leader is unsettling.
光是让肉盾来当团长
Saint Nin,
妮恩大人真的要待在 这种男人身边吗？
Yes, of course.
是啊 那当然
Because he's the strongest tank in the world!
因为他是世上最强的肉盾！
May I borrow the mic?
可以借用一下麦克风吗？
We're better than everyone in this room.
我们比在场的所有人都还厉害
You can laugh all you want.
你们想笑就笑吧
But those who laugh now will regret it later.
不过我一定会让现在笑的人后悔
We will surpass your expectations.
我们绝对会让你们的期待落空
We will conquer the entire Keild Labyrinth,
我们会将凯路德迷宫攻略到
a feat neither of the two major clans have achieved.
两大战团都无法突破的51层之上！
We will achieve our goal.
我们几个
That's a good-spirited young man.
真是个有气势的年轻人啊
I like people like that.
我最喜欢那样的人了
Leader…
团长
You came.
您也在场啊？
Yes.
是啊
Ike, I've told you not to underestimate newcomers.
艾克 就叫你不要太小看新人
That's a bad habit of yours.
这是你的缺点喔
But…
可是…
Rud, was it?
你叫做路德是吧？
I am Gothew, the leader of Black Dragon Fang.
我是黑龙之牙的团长 哥修
Pleasure to meet you.
请多指教
Just by shaking hands,
光靠握手就能知道
you can tell he's got extraordinary strength.
他拥有异于常人的强大力量
So this is the leader of Black Dragon Fang.
他就是黑龙之牙的团长
If this guy can conquer the labyrinth,
如果这家伙真的能攻略迷宫
then I'll consider an alliance with them.
我就打算跟他结为同盟喔
Stop hiding and say something.
别躲了 你也说些什么吧
Goodness.
真是的
I was going to pretend I wasn't around.
我本来打算装作不在 蒙混过关
Don't say that,
别这么说嘛
Miss Ryutel, the leader of White Tiger Claw.
白虎之爪的团长 卢特尔小姐
If this clan can conquer the labyrinth,
如果这个战团可以攻略迷宫的话
I might consider the possibility of an alliance.
我也可以考虑一下结盟的事喔
The condition being that you first successfully conquer the labyrinth.
不过前提是你们要成功攻略迷宫
That's what she said, Rud.
她是这么说的喔 路德
Show us you're not all bluff.
你可不要只是虚张声势喔
That was a great speech!
那个宣言真不错呢
Please let that go.
拜托你不要再说刚才的事了
By the way, why don't people know how strong you are?
话说大家为什么不知道你有多强啊？
Because generally speaking, you can't tell with just the eyes.
因为一般来说 光用眼睛看是看不出什么的
No… anyone with a certain level of strength can tell.
不 凡是有一定力量的人都看得出来
That you're not an ordinary person.
看得出你不是普通人
Rud, you must conquer the labyrinth.
路德 你一定要攻略迷宫喔
I don't like seeing you being treated as a joke.
因为我不喜欢你一直被别人当成笑话
Well then, I'm off to take a bath.
那么我去洗澡了
Don't give anyone any trouble.
不要给别人添麻烦喔
I know.
我知道啦
Master.
主人
You look tired.
你看起来很累呢
It's not often I get to speak in front of so many people.
因为很少有机会在那么多人面前讲话
But you were very impressive, Master.
不过主人刚才说的话很帅气喔
I was very happy to hear that.
我听了觉得很开心
Indeed.
是啊
And, well…
而且那个…
Thank you
谢谢你当时那样护着我
That made me really happy.
真的让我很高兴
Of course.
这是一定要的
You're my important comrade.
因为你是我重要的伙伴啊
Anyway, I just wanted to thank you.
总而言之 我只是想跟你道个谢而已
See you tomorrow.
那就明天见了
The labyrinth that even the two major clans couldn't conquer.
两大战团都无法攻略的迷宫
It won't be easy,
虽然知道这不是一件容易的事
but to protect my clan and friends,
但是为了守护战团和伙伴们
I must
我绝对…
conquer Keild Labyrinth.
会成功攻略凯路德迷宫的